<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on Sylvain's videography blog</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/tags/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on Sylvain's videography blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/tags/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Which framerate do I choose from for my videos?</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/30/which-framerate-do-i-choose-from/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/30/which-framerate-do-i-choose-from/</guid><description>Why is this article important for me? Choosing the right frame rate is important in video shooting because it affects the overall look and feel of the video. A higher frame rate gives smoother motion and a more lifelike quality, while a lower frame rate can give a more dramatic, cinematic feel. Frame rate also affects the amount of time required to capture a scene and the size of the final video file.</description></item><item><title>Shooting RAW video with Magic Lantern - Which camera to buy?</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/29/magic-lantern-raw-video-current-camera-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/29/magic-lantern-raw-video-current-camera-capabilities/</guid><description>Why is this article important for me? Shooting raw video refers to capturing video in its raw, unprocessed form directly from the camera&amp;rsquo;s image sensor. This allows for more flexible post-production editing and color correction since the data is not compressed or processed. Raw video files are often much larger than standard video files, but provide higher image quality and greater color depth. The benefit of shooting raw video is that it allows for greater creative control and the ability to make adjustments without losing image quality.</description></item></channel></rss>