<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on Huabing Blog</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/categories/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on Huabing Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/categories/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Subtitles generation with Davinci Resolve</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/26/subtitles-generation-davinci-resolve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/26/subtitles-generation-davinci-resolve/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-am-i-trying-to-learn-through-this-experience">What am I trying to learn through this experience?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As a film editor, one of the most tedious and time-consuming tasks can be transcribing audio to text in order to create subtitles for your videos. While many video editing software programs, such as Adobe Premiere, have built-in transcription tools, the same feature is not always available in other programs, such as DaVinci Resolve. In order to streamline the editing process, many editors are turning to AI-powered transcription software as a solution. One such software is StoryToolkitAI, a plugin that can help editors work more efficiently by automatically transcribing audio and allowing them to search transcripts semantically with the help of AI. This plugin can be integrated with DaVinci Resolve, which makes the process of creating subtitles a lot more manageable.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="which-tool-am-i-going-to-use-for-this-experience">Which tool am I going to use for this experience?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I found StoryToolkitAI, an open-source plugin offers a variety of features that can aid in the film editing process. The ability to automatically transcribe audio in multiple languages and translate it to English on a local machine can save a lot of time and effort compared to manual transcription. Additionally, the ability to search transcripts semantically using AI can make it easier to find specific segments of dialogue within the transcript.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-did-my-experience-go">How did my experience go?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The integration with DaVinci Resolve Studio 18 via API allows for easy navigation and marking of timelines using the transcript. The feature of transcript segment groups allows grouping of transcription segments similar to marking in NLEs, and the ability to import subtitles directly into Resolve makes the workflow more efficient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ability to convert existing SRT files to transcripts and use them in the tool, export transcripts to multiple formats, and batch transcriptions using transcription queuing are additional useful features. The plugin also includes the ability to perform partial re-transcription of timelines/videos/audio files, which can come in handy in case of errors or mistakes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Overall, the StoryToolkitAI plugin is a powerful and efficient tool for film editors, and could be a great asset in streamlining the editing process and save a lot of time and effort.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vim-graphical-cheat-sheet">vim graphical cheat sheet&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="//img/2018-02-09-vim-tips/vi-vim-cheat-sheet.svg" alt="">
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Everything about Setting Up My Ubuntu Desktop</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/05/24/set_up_my_ubuntu_desktop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/05/24/set_up_my_ubuntu_desktop/</guid><description>Generate SSH Key Pair ssh-keygen -C &amp;quot;zhaohuabing@gmail.com&amp;quot; Shadowsocks Install shadowsokcs sudo apt-get install python3-pip sudo pip3 install shadowsocks Create config at config/shadowsocks.json, with the following content: { &amp;quot;server&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;remote-shadowsocks-server-ip-addr&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;server_port&amp;quot;:443, &amp;quot;local_address&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;127.0.0.1&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;local_port&amp;quot;:1080, &amp;quot;password&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;your-passwd&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;timeout&amp;quot;:300, &amp;quot;method&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;aes-256-cfb&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;fast_open&amp;quot;:false, &amp;quot;workers&amp;quot;:1 } Start a local socks proxy sudo sslocal -c config/shadowsocks.json -d start In case there is an openssl error, modify shadowsocks source file. sudo vi /usr/local/lib/python3.6/dist-packages/shadowsocks/crypto/openssl.py :%s/cleanup/reset/gc Convert shadowsocks socks proxy to http proxy</description></item><item><title>如何配置docker使用HTTP代理</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/03/13/use-docker-behind-http-proxy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/03/13/use-docker-behind-http-proxy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="ubuntu">Ubuntu&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="设置docker使用http-proxy">设置docker使用http proxy&lt;/h3>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>sudo /etc/default/docker
export http_proxy=&amp;quot;http://127.0.0.1:3128/&amp;quot;
export https_proxy=&amp;quot;http://127.0.0.1:3128/&amp;quot;
export HTTP_PROXY=&amp;quot;http://127.0.0.1:3128/&amp;quot;
export HTTPS_PROXY=&amp;quot;http://127.0.0.1:3128/&amp;quot;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre></description></item><item><title>Vim Tips</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/02/09/vim-tips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/02/09/vim-tips/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vim-graphical-cheat-sheet">vim graphical cheat sheet&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="//img/2018-02-09-vim-tips/vi-vim-cheat-sheet.svg" alt="">
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>如何使用非root用户执行docker命令</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/02/09/docker-without-sudo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2018/02/09/docker-without-sudo/</guid><description>Add the docker group if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t already exist: sudo groupadd docker Add the connected user &amp;ldquo;$USER&amp;rdquo; to the docker group. Change the user name to match your preferred user if you do not want to use your current user: sudo gpasswd -a $USER docker Either do a newgrp docker or log out/in to activate the changes to groups.</description></item></channel></rss>