<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tips on Sylvain's videography blog</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/categories/tips/</link><description>Recent content in Tips on Sylvain's videography blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/categories/tips/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Which framerate do I choose from for my videos?</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/30/which-framerate-do-i-choose-from/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/30/which-framerate-do-i-choose-from/</guid><description>Why is this article important for me? Choosing the right frame rate is important in video shooting because it affects the overall look and feel of the video. A higher frame rate gives smoother motion and a more lifelike quality, while a lower frame rate can give a more dramatic, cinematic feel. Frame rate also affects the amount of time required to capture a scene and the size of the final video file.</description></item><item><title>Shooting RAW video with Magic Lantern - Which camera to buy?</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/29/magic-lantern-raw-video-current-camera-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/29/magic-lantern-raw-video-current-camera-capabilities/</guid><description>Why is this article important for me? Shooting raw video refers to capturing video in its raw, unprocessed form directly from the camera&amp;rsquo;s image sensor. This allows for more flexible post-production editing and color correction since the data is not compressed or processed. Raw video files are often much larger than standard video files, but provide higher image quality and greater color depth. The benefit of shooting raw video is that it allows for greater creative control and the ability to make adjustments without losing image quality.</description></item><item><title>Canon 5D Mark III capable of 4K all along</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/28/canon-5d-mark-iii-4k-capable/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/28/canon-5d-mark-iii-4k-capable/</guid><description>Why is this article important for me? As someone who&amp;rsquo;s passionate about hardware and pushing it to it&amp;rsquo;s limits, I&amp;rsquo;ve always hated software limitations. This behaviour from big tech companies has always been very popular, but luckily, devoted modders are always there to save our products from being thrown away. That&amp;rsquo;s what happened to the Canon 5D Mark III camera, which thanks to the Magic Lantern mod, shows that it was always able to shoot 4K video.</description></item><item><title>The importance of Lighting in Videos</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/27/lighting-tips-in-videography/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/27/lighting-tips-in-videography/</guid><description>Why is this article important for me? As a filmmaker or videographer, one of the most important things to consider when creating a video is lighting. Lighting is crucial in setting the mood and atmosphere of the video and can greatly impact how viewers perceive the scene and the subject. In this article, the author discuss why lighting is so important in videos and how it can be used to enhance a scene and create the desired mood and atmosphere.</description></item><item><title>Subtitles generation with Davinci Resolve</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/26/subtitles-generation-davinci-resolve/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/26/subtitles-generation-davinci-resolve/</guid><description>What am I trying to learn through this experience? As a film editor, one of the most tedious and time-consuming tasks can be transcribing audio to text in order to create subtitles for your videos. While many video editing software programs, such as Adobe Premiere, have built-in transcription tools, the same feature is not always available in other programs, such as DaVinci Resolve. In order to streamline the editing process, many editors are turning to AI-powered transcription software as a solution.</description></item><item><title>My digital awareness sources</title><link>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/25/my-digital-awareness-sources/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sylvainsalgatheig.github.io/labveiltech/2023/01/25/my-digital-awareness-sources/</guid><description>Where do I find resources related to videography? As a filmmaker, there are so many aspects that you need to learn in order to master this skill. Nowadays, most filmmakers learn from reading information on the internet. I&amp;rsquo;m actually learning the same way; I feel like other people&amp;rsquo;s experiences are worth a lot, because you can avoid doing the mistakes they made, and thus save time in the process of learning this skill.</description></item></channel></rss>